Register of the Nym Wales papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Nym Wales papers
1931-1998
58002
Hoover Institution Archives
69 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 11 oversize folders, 1 oversize envelope, 1 album box, 2 slide boxes, 2 videocassettes (29.0 linear feet)
Personal and collected correspondence, speeches and writings, news dispatches, interviews, reports, memoranda, organizational records, and photographs relating to the Chinese communists; the industrial cooperative movement, student movement, and labor movement in China; the Sian incident, 1936; the Sino-Japanese Conflict; and Chinese art and literature.
Wales, Nym, 1907-1997.
Access
Collection open for research.
Use copies of some videorecordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to sound recordings or to view other videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1958 with additional increments received from 1982 to 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
*Nym Wales is the pseudonym of Helen Foster Snow, also known in various contexts as Peggy Snow, Hseuh Hai-lun, and Lo Fu.
1907 September 21 Born, Cedar City, Utah
1925-1927 Student, University of Utah
1931-1941 Lived in China and the Philippine Islands, held positions as a journalist, book reviewer, and editor
1932 Married Edgar Snow (divorced, 1949)
1934-1935 Student, Yenching University and Tsinghua University
1937 Visited the headquarters of Chinese Communist leaders in Yenan for four months
1937 Co-founder of Democracy magazine
1938 Co-founder of the Chinese Industrial Cooperative movement in Shanghai
1939 Author, Inside Red China
1941-1951 Board of Directors, American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives
1941 Co-author with Kim San, Song of Arian: The Life Story of an Asian Revolutionary
1941 Author, China Builds for Democracy: A Story of Cooperative Industry
1945 Author, The Chinese Labor Movement
1952 Editor, Red Dust: Autobiographies of Chinese Communists as Told to Nym Wales
1952 Author, Fables and Parables for the Mid-Century
1958-1961 Author and compiler, Historical Notes on China, 6 volumes designed to accompany the Nym Wales Collection at the Hoover Institution: Notes on the Chinese Student Movement, 1935-1936; Notes on the Sian Incident, 1936; Notes on Korea and the Life of Kim San; My Yenan Notebooks; Notes on the Left-Wing Painters and Modern Art in China; Notes on the Beginnings of the Industrial Cooperatives in China
1967 Author, Women in Modern China
1972 Author, The Chinese Communists (in part a reprint of Red Dust)
1972-1973 Travelled in the Far East, including mainland China
1984 Author, My China Years: A Memoir
1997 January 11 Died, Guilford, Connecticut
Scope and Content of Collection
Personal and collected correspondence, speeches and writings, news dispatches, interviews, reports, memoranda, organizational records, and photographs relating to the Chinese communists; the industrial cooperative movement, student movement, and labor movement in China; the Sian incident, 1936; the Sino-Japanese Conflict; and Chinese art and literature.
An increment added in 2011 includes Wales's unpublished manuscript, in which she gave penetrating insights into the occurrences in Tiananmen Square on June 4, 1989, Chinese-American relations, globalism, and a reflection on her eighty-second birthday in 1989; as well as her correspondence with Communist Chinese provincial organizations and friends within and outside the United States in the late 1980s and the early 1990s.
Separated Materials Note
Additional material constituting part of the Nym Wales Collection can be located by consulting the following Hoover Institution Library card catalogs: Main catalog, Integrated Book Collection catalog, Society Publications catalog, Serials catalog, Newspaper catalog; and in the East Asia Collection--Chinese catalog, Chinese periodical catalog, and particularly, the Special Collection card file.
Printed material of the following organizations and publications has been integrated into the society publication, serial, and newspaper collections of the library:
Allied Labor News
Amerasia
Asia
Asia and the Americas
Asian Horizen
C.B.I. Roundup
Central News Agency, Peiping Branch
China Aid Council, newsletter
China Air Mail
China at War
China Clipper
China Critic
China Defense League
China Defense League, newsletter
China Digest
China Forum (Shanghai)
China Information Bulletin
China Information Committee, news releases
China Information Service, newsletter
China Magazine
China Press Weekly
China Reference Series
China Today
China Weekly Review
China Welfare Appeal
China Youth
Chinese Affairs
Chinese delegation to the U.N., official press releases
Chinese Nation
Chinese News Service, special features and releases, Voice of China weekly edition
Chinese Opinions on Current Events
Chinese Press Editorials (Reuters translation)
Chinese Recorder
Chinese Workers' Correspondence
Chinese Workers' Pictorial
Chinese Writers Monthly
Chinese Youth
C.I.C. Newsletter
Chengtu News Bulletin
Committee for a Democratic Policy toward China, information bulletin
Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy
Contemporary China
Current Comment on Events in China
Daily Worker (London)
Democratic Youth
Far East Bulletin
Far East Spotlight
Far Eastern Mirror
Far Eastern Policy News
Far Eastern Quarterly
Far Eastern Review
Far Eastern Survey
Gung Ho News
Indian Information
Indusco Bulletin
Indusco C.I.C. News from China
Indusco, Inc. American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives
International Literature
International Press Correspondence
Korean Independence
Kuo Min News Agency
Labour Monthly
Left News
Nankai Social and Economic Quarterly
National Reconstruction Journal
New China Review
New China Weekly News Letter
News of China
Northwest Indusco News
Oriental Affairs (Shanghai)
The Outlook
Pacific Affairs
Pacific Digest
Peoples Age
Philippines Herald
Photo-History
The Sentinel
Service d'archives, bulletin mensuel
The Showdown (Shanghai)
Southwest Indusco News
Szechuan Weekly Bulletin
Tass translation service
United China Relief
Voice of China (China news by shortwave radio)
Voks Bulletin
Znamia
Chinese industrial cooperatives.; Art--China.; Chinese literature.; Communism--China.; Cooperative societies--China.; Fascism--China.; Labor movement--China.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; Youth movements--China.; China--Economic conditions--1912-1949.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; Industries--China.; China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; Journalists.; Video tapes.
- CHINESE INDUSTRIAL COOPERATIVES, 1936-1950, 1958 (Boxes 1-9)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, writings, speeches, records, and printed matter related to the establishment and development of the Chinese Industrial Cooperative (C.I.C. or INDUSCO) movement during the 1930s and 1940s and especially to the participation of Nym Wales (Helen Foster Snow), Edgar Snow, Rewi Alley, and Ida Pruitt. Part of this material forms the basis for Wales' China Builds for Democracy, published in 1941. A guide to the material, prepared by Nym Wales, appears at the beginning of the series.
  - "Notes on the Beginnings of the Industrial Cooperatives in China,", 1958 (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains mimeograph transcripts of reports, minutes, correspondence, and manuscripts, as well as notes prepared by Nym Wales as a guide to the use of the following material.
  - Correspondence of Nym Wales and Edgar Snow, 1936-1947 (Box 1)
    Arrangement
    The correspondence of Nym Wales and Edgar Snow has been kept together because many of the letters are addressed to or concern both parties. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Allen, Donald M., 1939, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Alley, Rewi, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Babcock, Mrs. W. R. (Polly), 1941 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Cameron, Mr., 1944 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Carlson, Evans F., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Carter, Edward C., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Chen, Han-seng, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Chen, S. J., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Chiang, Shu-Huan (Mrs. K. M. Lu), 1940 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Early, Donald M., 1942 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Fairfax-Cholmeley Elsie, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Fitch, George A., 1942 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Gollancz, Victor, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Herz, Henriette, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Hogg, George Aylwin, 1940, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - [Hooker], Helene M. (Organizing Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1941 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - Hsia, C. L., 1939 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - Hull, Cordell (Secretary of State), 1940 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - Jen, Chu-min, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 22)
    - Johnson, Delbert (American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1941 (Box-folder 1: 23)
    - Johnson, Nelson Trusler (Ambassador to China), 1938, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 24)
    - Kaufman, Arthur, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 25)
    - Kennard, J. Spencer, Jr., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 26)
    - Lapwood, E. Ralph, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 27)
    - Leacock, David (American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 1: 28)
    - Lem, Frank (Len Su-yi), 1939 (Box-folder 1: 29)
    - Liang, Hubert S. (Liang Shih-shun), 1938-1940 (Box-folder 1: 30)
    - Dr. Robert K. S. (Chinese Red Cross), 1940 (Box-folder 1: 31)
    - Liu, Kwang Pei, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 1: 32)
    - Liu, T. F., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 33)
    - Loomis, Helen (American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1941 (Box-folder 1: 34)
    - Lu, Kwang Mein, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 35)
    - Porter, Miss, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 36)
    - Pruitt, Ida (American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1939-1944, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 37)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franklin D.), 1942 (Box-folder 1: 38)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 39)
      Contains a copy of a petition.
    - Selsbee, Elizabeth (American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives), 1943 (Box-folder 1: 40)
    - Soong, T. V., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 41)
    - Sycip, Mrs. Alfonzo Z., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 42)
    - Tereshtenko, Valery J. (The Cooperative Project), 1942 (Box-folder 1: 43)
    - Tong, Hollington K., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 44)
    - Walsh, Richard J., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 45)
    - Webber, John W., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 46)
    - Woodman, Dorothy (Anglo-Chinese Cooperative Development Society), 1940, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 47)
    - Wu, Mr., 1940 (Box-folder 1: 48)
    - Yarnell, Admiral Harry E., 1942 (Box-folder 1: 49)
    - Yeh, T'ing (Commander of the New Fourth Army), 1939 (Box-folder 1: 50)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, undated (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Writings, 1938-1941 (Box 2)
    Contains the writings of Nym Wales arranged by literary form, then chronologically.
    - Articles and essays, 1938-1966
      - "Industrial Cooperatives Needed to Strengthen China," China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1938 December 24 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - "The Philippines Aid China's Industrial Cooperatives," by "A Manila Correspondent" (Nym Wales), China Weekly Review, 1939 June 24 (Box-folder 2: 2)
        Includes printed copy and typescript drafts with carbon copies.
      - "Outline of the Development of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," carbon copies of typescript draft, circa 1939 (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - "China's New Line of Industrial Defense," carbon copy of typescript draft, 1939 April (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - "A Suggestion for Medical Cooperatives and Cooperative Clinics in China," typescript draft, circa 1939 (Box-folder 2: 5)
      - "Emergency Wartime Industry for China," carbon copy of typescript draft, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2: 6)
      - "Industrial Cooperatives for Economic Defense," carbon copies of typescript drafts, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2: 7)
      - "A Guiding Genius in the Destinies of China," carbon copy of typescript draft, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2: 8)
        Includes annotations by Rewi Alley.
      - "The Guiding Genius Behind China's Industrial Cooperative Movement," carbon copies of typescript drafts, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2: 9)
      - "'Front Line Industry' and the International Industrial Cooperative Centers in China," typescript draft with carbon copy, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2: 10)
      - "The 'Bailie Boys' of China's Industrial Cooperatives," Manila World, drafts and printed copies, 1940 February 14-15 (Box-folder 2: 11)
      - "The Bailie Boys of China," Hong Kong Sunday Herald, drafts and printed copies, 1940 August 11 (Box-folder 2: 12)
      - "China's New Industrial Defense Line: An Account of the Development of Industrial Cooperatives in China," typescript draft, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2: 13)
      - "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," Sunday Tribune Magazine, printed copy, 1940s (Box-folder 2: 14)
      - "China's New Industrial Defense Line," typescript draft with carbon copies, circa 1940 (Box-folder 2: 15)
      - "A Thought for Bishop Gregorio Aglipay," poem, 1940 September 28 (Box-folder 2: 16)
        This poem was published in Democracia and Philippines Free Press. Includes printed copies of the poem with news clippings attached.
      - "Comments and Suggestions for the Promotion of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," carbon copy of typescript draft, 1940s (Box-folder 2: 17)
      - "Industrial Cooperatives for China's National Defense," incomplete copy of draft, 1940s (Box-folder 2: 18)
      - "A Story of Cooperatives in Asia. Gung Ho," Mother Earth Quarterly, photocopy, July 1966 (Box-folder 2: 19)
    - Pamphlets, circa 1939-1940
      - An Industrial Defense Line for China (Box-folder 2: 20)
        Also includes typescript drafts with carbon copies.
      - Chinese Industrial Cooperatives (Box-folder 2: 21)
        Contains notations by Nym Wales and possibly Edgar Snow.
    - Books, 1941
      - China Builds for Democracy, chapter drafts and notes, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 22-23)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Collected writings and speeches, 1938-1942 (Boxes 3-4)
    Arranged alphabetically by author, literary form (where the variety warrants it), and then chronologically.
    - Alley, Rewi, 1939-1949, undated
      - "Report on the Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," Manila Telegraph (sic), printed copy and carbon copy of typescript, 1939 February 28 (Box-folder 3: 1)
      - "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," Manila World, 1939 July 5-6 (Box-folder 3: 2)
        Contains a printed copy, mimeograph copy, and carbon copy of the typewritten transcript of a speech first given at Chengtu.
      - "Report on C.I.C. Work Seen in N.W.H.Q. [Northwest Headquarters] Area," typescript, 1939 January-February (Box-folder 3: 3)
      - "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives Gain Headway in Interior," China Press, printed copy, 1939 March 13 (Box-folder 3: 4)
      - "A Plan for the Development of Industrial Cooperatives in the Border Government Area of the North West Yennan Office C.I.C.," typescript, 1939 March 18 (Box-folder 3: 5)
      - "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives for a New Southeast," Tingchow, typescript with carbon copies, 1939 April 28 (Box-folder 3: 6)
      - "General Report on Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, May 1, 1939," Manila World, printed and carbon copy of typescript, 1939 June 13 (Box-folder 3: 7)
      - "The Chinese Industrial Co-operatives," Reprints from the China Journal, 1939 May (Box-folder 3: 8)
      - "Model Constitution for Chinese Industrial Cooperative Societies," Manila World, printed copies, 1939 May 19 (Box-folder 3: 9)
      - "Searching Old Trails for New Industry," China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1939 June 3 (Box-folder 3: 10)
      - "New Men--New Industries," Manila World, printed copy, 1939 September 5 (Box-folder 3: 11)
      - Speech before the finance department of the Kansu Provincial Government, Lanchow, Kansu, carbon copy of typewritten transcript, 1939 November 29 (Box-folder 3: 12)
      - "Some Comments on Work for C.I.C. 1940 Conference," mimeograph copy, 1940 July (Box-folder 3: 13)
      - "The Sungpan Valley Awakes," Asia, printed copy, 1940 January (Box-folder 3: 14)
      - "Two Years of Indusco,", 1940 (Box-folder 3: 15)
        Contains an autographed booklet and annotated carbon copies of typescript drafts.
      - "War-time Industry," South China Morning Post, printed transcript of speech, 1940 August 13 (Box-folder 3: 16)
      - "Shantan Bailie School," printed copy, 1949 (Box-folder 3: 17)
      - "The Engineer in Cooperative Society," typescript, undated (Box-folder 3: 18)
      - "Rebuilding China's Industry by Cooperatives," typescript with carbon copy, undated (Box-folder 3: 19)
      - "New Men and New Industries in China's New Northwest," carbon copies of typescript, undated (Box-folder 3: 20)
      - "Development of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives in the Northwest," printed copy, undated (Box-folder 3: 21)
      - Poems and stories, undated (Box-folder 3: 22)
    - Arnold, Dorothy, "From the Ashes of Devastation Rises the Phoenix of China's Industrial Cooperatives," Manila World, printed copy, 1939 September 12 (Box-folder 3: 23)
    - Bertram, James, "Chinese Industrial Co-operatives," World Telegraph (Manila), printed and typescript copies, 1939 April 6 (Box-folder 3: 24)
    - Buck, Pearl S., "Free China Gets to Work," Asia, printed copy, 1939 April (Box-folder 3: 25)
    - Carlson, Evans Fordyce, "Economic Democracy in China," Amerasia, reprint, 1941 March (Box-folder 3: 26)
    - Chen, Jack, "Progress of China's Industrial Cooperatives,", 1939 (Box-folder 3: 27)
      Includes various reproductions of a series of twenty annotated drawings.
    - Chiang, Madame Kai-Shek, "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," World Telegraph (Manila), printed copy, 1939 May 6 (Box-folder 3: 28)
    - Crouter, Natalie C. "A Drop in the Bucket," carbon copies of typescript, undated (Box-folder 3: 29)
    - Deane, Hugh. "Chengtu Cooperatives Chalk Up Big Gains After One Year of Activity," China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1940 February 24 (Box-folder 3: 30)
    - Durdin, F. Tillman. "Co-operatives Spreading Over China," Manila World, printed copy, 1939 August 15 (Box-folder 3: 31)
    - "Far from the maddening headlines...," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 3: 32)
    - Fischer, Galen M. "The Cooperative Movement in Japan," Pacific Affairs, printed copies, 1938 December (Box-folder 3: 33)
    - Foster, John B. "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives in the Far Southwest," China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1939 November 18 (Box-folder 3: 34)
    - Fowler, Bertram B. "China's Guerilla Industry," reprints from Survey Graphic, 1941 February (Box-folder 3: 35)
    - Gould, Randall, 1939-1940
      - "Industrial Hope for China," World Telegraph, printed copies, 1939 March 2 (Box-folder 3: 36)
      - "Co-ops Thrive in Mid-China River Valley," World Telegraph, printed copy, 1939 May 9 (Box-folder 3: 37)
      - "How China Learns to Build Anew," Christian Science Monitor, printed copy, 1940 January 30 (Box-folder 3: 38)
    - Graham, Dorothy, "China Offers a Solution," Manila World, printed copies, 1939 August 22 (Box-folder 3: 39)
    - Hadley, Watson, Jr., "Industrial Cooperatives Forward Reconstuction," China Press, reprints, 1939 October 10 (Box-folder 3: 40)
    - Hogg, George Aylwin, 1939-1943, undated
      - "C.I.C. Gold Mining and Washing in Southwest Shensi,", 1939 December 16 (Box-folder 4: 1)
        Contains a carbon copy of typescript with biographical note by Nym Wales attached.
      - "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives and Refugees from the Hopei Flood Areas," typescript with carbon copies, 1940 January 10 (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - "Personal History of K. M. Lu," carbon copy of typescript, 1940 March 14 (Box-folder 4: 3)
      - "C.I.C. Education in the Northwest," carbon copy of typescript, 1940 May 31 (Box-folder 4: 4)
      - "My Neighbors Build a City," carbon copy of typescript, 1940 June 2 (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - News release from Second Annual Conference of the Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, Chungking, typewritten transcript, 1940 July 13 (Box-folder 4: 6)
      - "Dragon's Iron," carbon copy of typescript, 1940 July 2 (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - "Lanchow, Co-operative Outpost," carbon copy of typescript, 1941 January (Box-folder 4: 8)
      - "Report on the Front Line Depot of Southeast Shansi," typescript, 1941 February (Box-folder 4: 9)
      - "War Weave," carbon copy of typescript, circa 1940-1941 (Box-folder 4: 10)
      - "Training Cooperative Leaders for China," Free World, reprint, 1943 June (Box-folder 4: 11)
      - "Enabling the Disabled," typescript with carbon copy, undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - Homer, Joy, "China's Industrial Cooperatives," Manila World, printed copies, 1939 October 3 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - Howard, Harry Paxton, "Cooperation in the Far East: Japanese, Chinese and Indian Cooperatives Prepare Way for Economic Democracy in Asia," Commonweal, printed copy, 1942 July 24 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - Kung, H. H. "Industrial Co-operatives and the War," World Telegraph, printed copy, 1939 March 3 (Box-folder 4: 15)
    - Lattimore, Owen, "The Bailie Schools of China," mimeograph transcript of speech, 1944 October 23 (Box-folder 4: 16)
    - Liang, Hubert S., "Impressions and Observations of China's Northwest," mimeograph copies, 1940 January 25 (Box-folder 4: 17)
    - Liang, Hubert S., "Industrial Co-operatives Revitalize China's Northwest," Manila World, printed and carbon copy of typescript, 1940 February 22 (Box-folder 4: 18)
    - Lin, Yutang, "The Birth of a New China," World Telegraph, printed copy, 1938 April (Box-folder 4: 19)
    - Liu, K. P., "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," World Telegraph, printed copy, 1939 May 13 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    - Liu, K. P., "Development of Chinese Industrial Co-operatives," carbon copy of typescript, 1940 July (Box-folder 4: 21)
    - Ma, Hai-Teh, "I Knew Dr. Norman Bethune," Democracia, printed copies, undated (Box-folder 4: 22)
      Note
      Author also known as Dr. George Hatem.
    - Mu, Hsin, "Cooperatives in the Shensi-Kansu-Ninghia Border District," Sing Tao Jih Pao, 1940 July 9 (Box-folder 4: 23)
    - Prutt, Ida, 1939-1940, undated
      - "China's Industrial Pioneers," China Journal, reprints, 1939 February (Box-folder 4: 24)
      - "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives," Manila World, printed copy, 1939 December 12 (Box-folder 4: 25)
      - "China's Industrial Wall," Survey Graphic, reprints, 1940 March (Box-folder 4: 26)
      - "Decentralized Industry," China Monthly, reprints, undated (Box-folder 4: 27)
      - "The Bailie School at Sandan," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 4: 28)
    - Roy, Andrew T., "The Northwest Fights," carbon copy of typescript, 1939 June (Box-folder 4: 29)
    - Simester, Edith, "Economic Reconstruction for Rural Workers in Fukien," China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1939 May (Box-folder 4: 30)
    - Sinclair, T. Lowry, Jr., "Through South China," typescript, undated (Box-folder 4: 31)
    - Smith, W. B., "China's Cash-&-Carry Industries," China Press Sunday Magazine, printed copies, 1939 February 12 (Box-folder 4: 32)
    - Smythe, Lewis, 1939-1942